CENTER FOR COMMUNITY STUDIES RECORDS (UA652) 1825-1976
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
- Activities and Programs, 1825-1976; 2; 12
  - Student Questionnaires, 1939 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Student Questionnaires, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Student Questionnaires, 1940 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Student Questionnaires, 1952 March 20 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Survey of High School Student Activities, 1952 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Surveys on Social Agencies, Undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Census Classification Project, Photograph Map of the City of Albany, 1825 (Oversized 15)
- Publications, 1940-1968; 3; 1.14
  This series includes newsletters, reports, and studies published both by the Center for Community Studies and other organizations. Newsletters include the Center for Community Studies' Education Newsletter and the State University College of Albany's Faculty Bulletin of Information (F.B.I.). This series also includes articles, surveys and publications on prisons (such as Sing Sing), and segregation.
  - The ABC’s of Local School Districts in New York State, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - The Academically Talented: Problems and Programs, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Alpenfels, Ethel J., Sense & Nonsense About Race, New York, 1946 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Alpenfels, Ethel and W.M. Krogman, Race Against Time: An Introductory Anthropology for Young, Undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - American Unity: To Secure These Rights, 1947 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - America’s Tenth Man, Southern Regional Council, 1947 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Amsterdam Survey, Undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Bienstok, Theodore, and William C. Sayres, Problems of Secondary Education in International Perspectives, 1959 February (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Center for Community Studies, Newsletter, 1952 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Charting Intercultural Education, 1954-1955 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Cole, Stewart G., and Helen G. Troger, How Can Majority and Minority Groups Contribute to Democracy? Democratic Discussions No. 10, 1943-1944 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - College-Community Relationships in New York State, 1953 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Community, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Coolidge,Calvin, Address by the President (1925), Jewish Contributions to American Democracy, 1940 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Education Newsletter, 1951-1953 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Faculty Bulletin of Information, 1952 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Fielder, Miriam Foster, “A Study of the Socio-Economic Status of a Group of Public School Children with Hearing Defects,” Child Development 22.3, 1951 September (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Fielder, Miriam Foster, “Teachers’ Problems with Hard of Hearing Children,” Journal of Educational Research, 1949 April (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Fellowship House, Extinguish Hatred, Philadelphia, Undated (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Formation of Educational Policies: A Comparative Analysis, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Grier, Eunice, and George, Race Relations in the Albany-Troy Area: A Profile for 1957, 1957 November (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Halsey, Margaret, Some of My Best Friends are Soldiers, New York, 1944 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Hightower, Estelle, Race Relations in the South, New York, 1942 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Horner, Harlan H., Education in New York State, 1784-1954 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Improving InterGroup Relations in School and Community Life, 1946 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Intercultural Education through the Social Studies, 1945 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Johnson, Eric A., Intolerance, New York City, 1947 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - The July 1953 Prophylaxis Program for Poliomyelitis in Chemung Audsteuben Counties, 1954 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - McEntire, Davis, and Robert B. Powers, A Guide to Race Relations For Police Officers, Police Training Bulletin, Department of Justice, State of California, 1947 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Members of the Staff of Junior High School 47, “A New Approach To The Education of Two and Three Year Old Deaf Children,” Volta Review, 1949 May-June (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Nelson, Robert L., The Negro in Athletics, New York, 1968-1969 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Nelson, Rose K., and Dorothy L. Cole, The Negro’s Contribution to Music in America, New York, 1941 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Newsletter from the State University of New York, 1952 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Preparing the Offender in the Institutions of the New York State Department of Corrections, 1954 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - The Problem of Violence, Undated (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Sing Sing Prison, 1953 (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - State Education Department, 1952 (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - A Survey of the Humanagement of a Public School System, 1949 (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - Survey Graphic: Segregation, 1947 (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - Vickery, William E., and Morris Edward Opler, “A Redefinition of Prejudice for Purposes of Social Science Research,” Human Relations 1.4, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 40)